Now let's talk about
Giờ hãy nói về
a few solution architectures
một vài kiến trúc giải pháp
you can encounter with Amazon ECS.
bạn có thể gặp với Amazon ECS.
So the first one are ECS tasks invoked by Event Bridge.
Đầu tiên là ECS task được gọi bởi Event Bridge.
So for example, say we have an Amazon ECS cluster,
Ví dụ, chúng ta có một Amazon ECS cluster
it's backed by Fargate, and we have S3 buckets.
chạy trên Fargate và có các S3 bucket.
Our users are going to upload objects into our S3 buckets,
Người dùng sẽ tải đối tượng lên S3 bucket,
And these S3 buckets can be, for example,
và các S3 bucket này có thể, ví dụ,
integrated with Amazon Event Bridge
tích hợp với Amazon Event Bridge
to send all the events to it.
để gửi tất cả sự kiện tới đó.
And Amazon Event Bridge can have a rule
Amazon Event Bridge có thể có rule
to run ECS tasks on the go.
để chạy ECS task khi cần.
Now, when ECS tasks are going to be created,
Khi các ECS task được tạo,
they will have an ECS task role associated with them,
chúng sẽ có ECS task role đi kèm,
and from the task itself
và từ chính task
what it can do is that it can get the objects, process it,
nó có thể lấy object, xử lý
and then send the results into Amazon DynamoDB.
và gửi kết quả vào Amazon DynamoDB.
And that is thanks to the fact
Đó là nhờ vào việc
that we have an ECS task role associated with it.
chúng ta gán ECS task role.
And so effectively here, what we've done
Như vậy, chúng ta đã
is that we've created a serverless architecture
tạo ra một kiến trúc serverless
to process images, or to process objects,
để xử lý hình ảnh hay các object
from your S3 buckets using a Docker container.
từ S3 bucket bằng Docker container.
And that is using Amazon Event Bridge ECS
Điều này dùng Amazon Event Bridge ECS
in the Fargate mode, as well as an ECS task role
ở chế độ Fargate và ECS task role
to talk to Amazon S3 and Amazon DynamoDB.
để tương tác với Amazon S3 và Amazon DynamoDB.
Another architecture using, again, Event Bridge,
Một kiến trúc khác cũng dùng Event Bridge
is to use an Event Bridge schedule.
là dùng lịch của Event Bridge.
So we have an Amazon ECS cluster
Chúng ta có một Amazon ECS cluster
backed by Fargate and Amazon Event Bridge,
chạy Fargate và Event Bridge,
and we schedule a rule to be triggered every 1 hour.
và chúng ta đặt lịch để rule kích hoạt mỗi giờ.
Now, this rule is going to run ECS tasks for us in Fargate,
Rule này sẽ chạy ECS task trên Fargate,
and so that means that every 1 hour,
nghĩa là mỗi giờ
a new task will be created in our Fargate cluster,
một task mới sẽ được tạo trong Fargate cluster
and the task can do whatever we want.
và task có thể thực hiện bất cứ việc gì.
For example, we can create an ECS task role
Ví dụ, chúng ta tạo một ECS task role
with access to Amazon S3, and therefore our task,
có quyền truy cập Amazon S3, do đó task của chúng ta
our Docker container, our program can, for example,
container Docker, chương trình của chúng ta có thể
do every 1 hour some batch processing
mỗi giờ chạy xử lý hàng loạt
against some files in Amazon S3.
đối với các file trong Amazon S3.
And again, all of that architecture is fully serverless.
Tất cả kiến trúc này hoàn toàn serverless.
A last example is using ECS and an SQS queue,
Ví dụ cuối cùng là dùng ECS với SQS queue,
so we could have a service on ECS with two ECS tasks,
chúng ta có một service ECS với hai ECS task,
and messages are being sent into an SQS queue,
và các message được gửi vào SQS queue,
and the service itself is pulling for messages
service sẽ pull message
from the SQS queue, and processing them.
từ SQS queue và xử lý.
We can enable ECS Service Auto Scaling
Chúng ta có thể bật ECS Service Auto Scaling
on top of this service.
cho service này.
That means that, for example, the more messages we have
Điều đó nghĩa là càng nhiều message
in our SQS queue, the more tasks we're going to have
trong SQS queue, càng nhiều task
into our ECS service, thanks to auto-scaling.
trong ECS service nhờ auto-scaling.
Another integration is when you want to use Event Bridge
Một tích hợp khác là khi bạn muốn dùng Event Bridge
to actually intercept events from within your ECS cluster.
để bắt các sự kiện bên trong ECS cluster.
So, for example, say you wanted to react
Ví dụ bạn muốn phản ứng
to tasks being exited.
khi task kết thúc.
In that case, any task exiting or starting
Khi đó, bất kỳ task nào thoát hoặc khởi chạy
in your ECS cluster can be triggered as an event
trong ECS cluster đều có thể phát sự kiện
in Event Bridge, and it will look like this.
đến Event Bridge và trông như thế này.
For example, the ECS task state change for "stopped"
Ví dụ, sự kiện ECS task state change cho trạng thái "stopped"
and the stopped reason.
kèm lý do dừng.
Then from there, for example, we could alert an SNS topic
Từ đó chúng ta có thể gửi cảnh báo lên SNS topic
and send emails to your administrators.
và gửi email cho quản trị viên.
So, bottom line, Event Bridge does allow you to understand
Tóm lại, Event Bridge giúp bạn hiểu
the lifecycle of your containers in your ECS cluster.
vòng đời container trong ECS cluster.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture.
Được rồi, bài học đến đây.
I hope you liked it, and I will see you in the next lecture.
Hy vọng bạn thích và hẹn gặp lại ở bài giảng tiếp theo.